Attention, everyone!
Jim and l, on behalf
of the Party Planning
Committee have an. . .
Too loud.
Too, too loud. Too loud.
But effective. Look.
On behalf of Jim and l,
Merry Christmas.
ALL: Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. Good.
My diabolical plot is
on hold for Christmas.
My heart just melts
with the sound of
children singing.
(LAUGHlNG)
Not really. l'm just tired.
The days are short.
l don't know.
Maybe l'm depressed.
lt is time to
unveil the tree.
You know, Oscar,
every time l make
this lasagna
people ask me if
it's a family recipe,
but really, l just get
the recipe from the box.
That's funny.
ls it funny?
l thought it was more
interesting than funny.
l think my water
just broke.
That's too funny.
Oscar and
the warehouse guy.
Go, Oscar!
Go, gay warehouse guy!
Here's Santa!
Hey, little girl,
what would you
like for Christmas?
Ooh ! You have been a very
naughty girl, l see.
Michael, we already
have a Santa. Phyllis.
What the hell is going on?
Phyllis, Jim?
Phyllis is Santa?
Yeah.
Phyllis.
Yeah. l told her
a long time ago
she could do it.
Take it back.
That is absurd.
No. l'm not gonna do that.
No, Jim, come on !
l think she's
doing a good job.
lt's insane!
A woman Santa?
Where does it stop?
No! Jim, this may
be the last Christmas
that we have here.
Doesn't it make you
a tiny bit anxious,
me not playing Santa?
Come on !
l'm not gonna go tell Phyllis
that she can't be Santa.
Fine. Then do it anonymously.
Ransom-note style. You can. . .
You know what?
l have a bunch of letters
cut out of magazines
in my desk.
You can use those.
lf this were Russia,
yeah, sure,
everybody would
go to one Santa,
and there would be
a line around the block,
and once
you sat on her lap
and she asked you
what you wanted,
you would say,
probably, freedom,
at which point
the KGB would arrest you
and send you to Siberia.
lt's a good thing
Russia doesn't exist anymore.
Ho! Ho! Ho!
Why pay more
to sit next to old
Trannie Claus over there
when you can sit on my lap?
Phyllis is only
pretending to be a man.
l'm the real thing !
Sit down on my lap
and there will be no doubt!
Okay.
No, it's not,
like, penis-wise.
Hello, little boy!
What's your name?
Michael, it's me, Kevin.
Phyllis says
l'm too big for her lap.
Oh, l am so sorry
that Phyllis hates you
and hates your body,
but Santa
remembers a reindeer
that was just a tiny
bit different as well.
When can l sit on your lap?
Right now!
Come on over here, big boy!
There we go! Oh, my God.
That's really comfortable.
What would you
like for Christmas,
little boy?
l don't know.
l didn't know you
were gonna ask me that.
Well, what did you think
was going to happen?
l didn't know.
Nobody's ever let me
sit on their lap before.
(SOFTLY) All right,
just say some toys, please.
Can you give me some choices?
'Cause l really
don't want to mess up
on this list.
Damn it, Kevin. Come on.
What about if l
tell you the things
l don't want?
Okay, get off!
Get off! Off!
(GROANS)
Oh, God !
l didn't even get to
tell you what l wanted.
Okay, you know what you get?
You get a thousand
helium balloons
attached to you
so Santa doesn't have
to go through this again.
Awesome.
Well?
l'm trying, Phyllis.
You're Santa.
The only Santa.
That's what l want.
You promised me this.
Don't make me
get Bob involved.
What would Bob do?
Never mind.
l shouldn't have said that.
Does it hurt?
lt stings a lot.
Hmm.
l keep trying
to figure out who's
sending me these gifts.
l know, right?
So far no one
will admit to it.
(CHUCKLES)
ls it you?
Yeah !
Totally.
l admit it. lt's me.
(LAUGHS) Seriously?
Seriously?
Are you serious?
ls. . . What. . . ls it you?
Yeah. Totally serious.
l'm your Secret Santa.
Busted !
(LAUGHS)
There he is.
Hey, man.
ls Matt around?
l've got his check.
Matt is on a delivery.
Just leave it here.
l'll take it.
l'll just wait for him.
Matt's a pretty
good-looking dude,
don't you think?
l'll just leave
it here with you.
Come here!
Come here! Come here!
l'm doing
something over here.
Come on ! Ah !
Ho! Ho! Ho!
MlCHAEL: Come on,
l need this.
Come over here!
Just sit down !
No, no, no,
no, no, no!
ls everything okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Ryan and l are
just having some fun.
Can l just talk to
you for a second?
Yeah.
No, now.
Okay, what?
You can't yell out,
"l need this, l need this,"
as you pin down
an employee on your lap.
Okay. You know what, Jim?
With two Santas in the room,
things get ruthless.
Yeah.
Do you understand?
You forced my hand.
Michael, it's Phyllis.
We want Phyllis as Santa.
Do we? Do we?
ls that what we want?
Why don't we
take a vote on it?
Great.
Hey! Okay, everybody.
The office is
being pulled apart.
l realize that.
There are traditions at stake.
And there are women. . .
Who wants Phyllis as Santa?
No, no, no! Wait! No!
There are other choices.
There's information that we. . .
Are you kidding me, Kevin?
After you almost killed me?
Michael, l had you.
l just want to try Phyllis.
And if you want
Michael as Santa,
raise your hand.
Can l get you
some punch?
l. . . No, l'll get some punch.
That looks delicious.
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG)
KELLY: Michael !
Excuse me.
Whoever has been sending me
the parts to this gun,
l think you sent me a gear
instead of a trigger.
How do you know it's a gun?
What else does it look like?
Not a gun.
Well, l don't have
all the pieces yet.
Well, unless
the missing piece is a gun,
you don't have a gun.
Not a gun.
ln the North Pole,
l spend many nights alone
tinkering with toys.
So today,
let's put a twinkle in
old Kris Kringle's eye.
Let the party begin !
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG)
l don't ask for
much for Christmas.
l really don't.
lt's not like
l am begging people
to buy me diamonds
and broach pendants.
Oh !
"Buy me something expensive,
or l'm gonna kill myself."
That's not. . .
l don't care about that!
All l want to be is Santa.
And you want to take that
away from me, fine.
Go ahead.
But when
you need my help
because l am
ruining everything,
don't look at me!
Behold,
Jesus Christ.
And l bring to you
glad Christmas tidings.
l want to remind everyone
the true meaning
of Christmas.
Those of you who
wish to join me,
that's great.
l am excited by that,
and those of you who don't,
l forgive you,
but l never forget.
Wow, Michael.
This must be obvious
how wrong this is.
The Antichrist.
Okay, you can't. . .
(EXCLAlMS)
Look, you cannot
push religion.
But l can push drugs in here.
ls that what
you're saying?
No.
Well, you have to
pick one or the other.
Your choice.
Pick your poison.
Get back to me.
ln the meantime,
l am going to
spread my goodness
all over this company!
Hey, Phyllis?
Could you not reveal to Erin
that l'm her secret Santa?
All right, sweetie,
l'll just tell her
it's Michael.
Okay.
BOTH: (SlNGlNG)
I saw three ships
come saiIing in
PAM: Have you talked to him?
What?
Matt.
OSCAR: ls it that obvious?
No. Hey.
Hmm.
Good pâté, right?
Oscar made it.
Have you met Oscar?
l don't think so.
Hey, Oscar, come here.
Oscar, this is Matt,
and Matt loves your pâté.
l had some.
Oscar's pâté's great.
l could eat it all day,
every day. Mmm.
How come the good ones
are never straight, right?
Okay, Pam.
Okay.
Yes. They're the only
two gay guys l know.
But they should be together.
This just arrived
from the Dunder Mifflin
North Pole branch.
We don't have
a North Pole branch.
ldiot!
Uh-oh!
What's Dwight gonna get?
What is it?
Yes!
Oh, yes! lt's space garbage.
Dwight's gonna be abIe
to build himself a friend.
Deck the halls
with crappy gifts
And Stanley,
you've been very
good this year.
l have.
Yeah, except for
cheating on your wife.
AduItery's a sin.
Look it up
in the BibIe, peopIe.
What'd he get?
He got scented candles.
WeII, that's appropriate.
A lot of fire
where you're going.
Better get used to it.
You're going to H-E-L-L,
doubIe hockey sticks.
Going to hell, Stanley.
ANGELA: Amen.
And this brings us
to you, little one.
I can't see from here, peopIe.
Somebody shout it out.
Don't make me get up.
lt's fabric.
l really wanted this.
That's fantastic!
You can make another dress
that goes past your feet.
Andy, was this you?
lt's a secret.
No, Andy had Erin.
PHYLLlS: lt was a secret.
PAM: Michael !
PHYLLlS: You. . .
What? Was l not
supposed to say?
What? Turn it back on.
No.
(DOOR CLOSlNG)
DAVID: Yes, Michael.
What is so urgent?
David, guess who l am
sitting here dressed as.
I'm not going to guess.
You can tell me,
or I wiII hang up.
l will give you a hint.
His last name is Christ.
He has the power of flight.
He can heal leopards.
Michael...
l am Jesus, David,
and you know why?
Because Phyllis,
a woman, has uslurped
my role as Santa.
Michael...
What?
This is a very,
very bad time.
Really? What's going on?
Stephanie,
can you hop off, pIease?
STEPHANlE: Sure, David.
What the hell?
How rude! Does she do
that all the time?
ERlN: Do you want me off
this call too, Michael?
Hey, what? Get off!
Get off the phone!
DAVlD: Listen,
I shouIdn't teII you this,
but the company has a buyer.
The board
will have no choice
but to approve,
and they are going
to clean house.
What does that mean?
l'll be fired.
Well, can't Alan protect you?
Alan will be out, too.
All of us.
All of us?
Goodbye, Michael.
Oh, my God.
MlCHAEL: Earlier today,
this office needed a Santa.
And then it
needed a second Santa.
And then it needed a Jesus.
And now,
it needs a Michael.
And that's one suit
Phyllis cannot fit into.
Hey, how's everybody doing?
Not great.
You heckled Santa
for an hour and a half.
That was a different guy.
That was Jesus.
Jesus sort of
ruined the party.
Hurt, petulant Jesus.
Are you serious?
That is so offensive.
You know what's
even more offensive,
is bailing on this party
because some jerk ruined
the first part of it.
Dwight, come here.
Here's my debit card.
l want you to go pick
up a bunch of pizzas
and meet me in
the conference room.
What's your pin number?
l don't want to say.
But it's fun
to stay at the. . .
lt's fun to stay at the. . .
Where?
Holiday lnn. l don't. . .
(HUMMlNG)
l thought that
you would like it.
lt was a little much, Andy.
Well, it's the thought
that counts.
What were you thinking?
l suppose a gentleman
might throw in the towel
at this point.
Guess what.
Not gonna happen.
You know what?
Christmas isn't
about Santa or Jesus.
lt's about the workplace.
All of you feel
like my family.
Ryan, you are my son,
and Pam, you're my wife,
and Jim. . .
And Angela and Phyllis,
you are my grandmas.
And Stanley,
you're our mailman.
And l can't help but look
at all of your wonderful,
beautiful faces
and think, "How could
they do this to us?"
What?
(ALL MURMURlNG)
How could we do
what to you?
That's not. . .
Never. . . Nothing.
Why would we. . .
We deserve to know.
MlCHAEL: l didn't
say anything !
We're going out of business!
What?
ANDY: You are kidding me.
Wait, wait, wait.
Who said that?
David told me on the phone.
David told me.
ANDY: When?
When did he tell you, today?
Earlier today,
he said we have been sold.
JlM: What?
(YELLlNG)
JlM: Dwight! Jesus.
PAM: Come on !
Michael, wait.
So they said we are sold.
David is gone,
Alan is gone.
We're all gone.
Okay, but we
haven't gone under.
We've been sold,
and that can mean
many different things.
lt's hard for me to
imagine a scenario
where Meredith Palmer
keeps her job and
David Wallace does not.
No offense, Meredith.
No, l get it.
l'll call him.
l'll call David.
No you won't,
because he's not
picking up his phone.
Yes, l will,
because l always know
how to get through to him.
He told me where
his kids go to school.
l call the school.
l tell them
l'm the pediatrician.
They patch me
through to his secretary.
l use my little girl voice.
(EXCLAlMS)
DAVID: Hey, sweetie,
what is it?
lt's not sweetie.
lt's Michael Scott.
What the hell?
Stephanie,
could you hop off, please?
Michael, l have never...
David. . .
...never, ever...
David, you are
on speakerphone
with the entire branch
and the warehouse.
Hi, David.
ALL: Hey, David.
Hi, everyone.
David, they do not believe me
when you told me
that everyone was canned.
You weren't supposed
to teII anyone, MichaeI.
Well, l think
we're past that now.
I am not supposed...
Okay, fine.
Guys, l was really
onIy taIking
about AIan, myseIf,
and a few other
execs you don't know.
Oh, my God.
David, that's horrible.
How about us? lt's Meredith.
By the way, your wife
is a very lucky woman.
Look,
they're buying the company
for the distribution.
You guys are the onIy thing
about this company that works.
So congratulations.
We're not fired?
No. Congratulations.
All right!
Yeah !
(ALL CHEERlNG)
Come on !
lt's a Christmas miracle!
DWlGHT: Yeah !
(SlNGlNG) WaIk a IoneIy road
Only one that
l have ever known
Don't know where it goes
But it's all to me
and l walk alone
lt's true.
Yes.
DWIGHT: We aII waIk aIone.
Jim.
My shadow's the onIy one
That walks beside me
My shaIIow heart's...
Wow.
Yeah. That was the idea.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, man.
(SlNGlNG) Christmas tree
Thou Ieaves are so unchanging
Of course!
You got it?
What is that?
l have no idea.
Well, maybe those will help.
Michael, please. Come on.
Sorry.
Sure.
Nice to meet you, Oscar.
Nice to meet you, Mark.
lt's Matt.
Right, Matt.
l know what l'm doing, Pam.
Oh, man !
l can use this
for so many nuts.
Macadamias,
Brazil nuts, pecans,
almonds, clams, snails.
Hi, Santa.
Hi, Michael.
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
l'd like to make a wish.
What?
l would like an Xbox
and a TV that's
compatible with an Xbox.
And l'm sorry.
An Xbox it is,
because l've decided
you're a good boy.
Scott, what in the hell
is going on here?
No, no, no.
We worked it out.
You called Bob? Phyllis!
l'm sorry. l'm really sorry.
lt was earlier today.
Okay.
Hi, sweetheart.
You okay, baby?
l'm good, baby.
Oh, God. Get a room, Santas.
DWlGHT: Thank you, Santa.
Okay, happy holidays.
lt's real slippery out here.
Oh, my God.
Twelve drummers drumming.
Merry Christmas, Erin.
Take it away, boys!
(RHYTHMlC DRUMBEATS)